American Locomotive Company (ALCO) Records
American Locomotive Company (ALCO) Records
- Financial material
  - American Locomotive Company
    - General
      - Stockholders' Meeting, 1955 (Box 47)
- Published material
  - Financial
    - Semi-Annual Statements, 1926-1936; 11 folders (Box 47)
    - Annual Report, 1902
      Sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Annual Report, 1908
    - Annual Report, 1914-1941 (Box 48)
    - Annual Report, 1942-1953; 1955-1963 (Box 49)
    - Annual Report, General Steel Castings Corporation, 9th, 1937 (Box 49)
    - Annual Report, Worthington, 1964; 1966 (Box 49)
    - Annual Reports, duplicates, extra copies of Alco's annual reports (Box 50)
    - Annual Reports, duplicates, extra copies of Alco's annual reports (Box 51)
    - Annual Reports, duplicates, extra copies of Alco's annual reports (Box 52)
  - Publicity
    - Press Kits
      - Century 628 Locomotive, 8 folders (Box 53)
      - Diesel Engine, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Drilling Rig, 1955 (Box 53)
      - Hi-Qua-Led Steel (Box 53)
      - India Shipments, 1957-1962; 5 folders (Box 53)
      - Locomotives (Box 53)
      - Pakistan Shipments (Box 53)
      - Products, 1958-1959 (Box 53)
      - Steel Springs, 1957 (Box 53)
      - Tours
        - Auburn and Schenectady, 1963; 3 vols. (Box 53)
        - Los Angeles Warehouse, 1956 (Box 53)
        - North Bergen Warehouse, 1959 (Box 53)
        - Schenectady, 1958 (Box 53)
    - Pamphlets
      - Alco - General (Box 53)
      - Converting Schenectady Plant to Make Tanks (Box 53)
      - Diesel Generators (Box 53)
      - Diesel Generators (Box 54)
      - Diesel Engines
        - General (Box 54)
        - 251, 1 folder, 10 vols. (Box 54)
      - Exports
        - India (Box 54)
        - Locomotives (Box 54)
      - Heat Exchangers (Box 54)
      - An Immediate Solution: Railroads, 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Industrial Progress (Box 54)
      - Invitations (Box 54)
      - Locomotives
        - Century, 2 folders (Box 54)
        - General, 2 folders (Box 54)
      - M-7 Tank (Box 54)
      - Open-Die Forgings, Latrobe (Box 54)
      - Welcome to Alco, Schenectady (Box 54)
    - Advertising leaflets, 2 folders, 3 vols. (Box 54)
  - Periodicals
    - Alco Review (Box 55)
    - Installment Credit Guide, 1966; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Labor Law Reports, 1962 (Box 55)
    - Quest (Box 55)
    - Railway Locomotives and Cars (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Heat Transfer Tables, 2 folders (Box 55)
- Bound materials
  - Alco Calendar, 1949; 1 volume (Box 56)
  - Engineering diagrams, 1 volume (Oversize 12A)
  - Product data and information; operation and maintenance manuals, 18 vols. (Box 56)
    Tool Catalog for Road and Switcher Locomotives
    Renewal Parts Diesel Locomotive Catalog
    Alco – GE DRP Bulletins
    Diesel Engine Maintenance Manual
    Servicing and Maintaining Manual for Various Diesel-Electric Locomotives
    Alco Products, Inc. Product Data Catalog
    Alco Products Information
    Governor Maintenance Manual
    Facilities and Capabilities Binder
    Alco Nuclear Capability
    Servicing and Maintaining Alco-GE Diesel-Electric Road Locomotives
    Electrical Equipment for New South Wales Government Railways Class 45 Diesel-Electric Locomotives
    Fuel Injection Equipment Maintenance Manual
    Principles of Electrical Equipment Instruction Guide 2
    Turbosupercharger Maintenance Manual
    Electrical Manual #1
    Diesel Engine Section – New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad
  - Operation and maintenance manuals, 29 vols. (Box 57)
    Instruction: Diesel-Electric Railroad Locomotive
    Maintenance Manual: 1500 HP Road Locomotive Units
    Renewal Parts for Electric Equipment used on Diesel-Electric Locomotives
    Maintenance Instructions: Electrical Equipment for Diesel-Electric Locomotive
    Instructions: Diesel-Electric Locomotive
    Operation and Service Manual: 1500 HP Road Switcher, 1500 HP Freight Locomotive, 2000 HP Passenger Locomotive
    Operating Manual: 1500 HP Road Locomotive Units
    Switching Locomotives: 660 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Road Switcher
    Operating Manual: 1600 HP Freight-Passenger Locomotive (2 copies)
    Maintenance Manual: 660 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Road Switcher (2 copies)
    Operating Manual: 1500 HP Road Switcher (3 copies)
    Operation and Service Manual: 660 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Road Switcher
    Switching Locomotives: 660 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Road Switcher Instruction Manual Bulletin 105-A (3 copies)
    Mechanical Maintenance Manual: Road Locomotives with Model 244 Engines
    Operating Manual: Model RSD-5 1600 HP Road Switcher 6 motors
    Operating Manual: 1800 HP Road Switchers Models RS-11 and RS-12 (3 copies)
    Operating Manual: Model RSD-4 1600 HP Road Switcher 6 Motors (2 copies)
    Operating Manual: Model RS-3 1600 HP Road switcher
    Operating Manual: Diesel-Electric Road Switcher 1500 HP
    Electrical Operating Instructions: Diesel-Electric 1000 HP Switching Locomotive
    Diesel-Electric Road Locomotive Instruction Book Bulletin No. 303
    Operating Instructions 44 Ton, 380 HP Diesel-Electric Railroad Locomotive Class B-B-88/88-4GE733
    Operating Manual 200 HP Road Locomotive Units (2 copies)
    Diesel Locomotive Instruction Book Bulletin No. 105-A
    American Locomotive Company Manual De La Locamotora
    Operating Manual: 2400 HP Road Switcher Model RSD-7
    Inspection and Lubrication Instructions: 660 HP switcher, 1000 HP Switcher, 1000 HP Road Switcher
    Operating Manual: Model RS-3 1600 HP Road Switcher
    Operating Manual: Model RSD-4 1600 HP Road Switcher 6 Motors
  - Operation and maintenance manuals, 17 vols. (Box 58)
    Operating and Maintenance Manual
    660 Volt Locomotive, August 1930: Chicago, Rock Island, and Pacific Railroad
    300 HP Oil-Electric Locomotive Equipment, January 1933: Lehigh Valley Railway Company
    300 HP Oil-Electric Locomotive Equipment, January 1932: Jay Street Connecting Company Railway Company
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, July 1935: New Haven
    300 HP Oil-Electric Locomotive Equipment, March 1932: Mare Island
    600 HP Oil-Electric Locomotive Equipment, November 1933: LV-B&M-DL&W
    600 HP Oil-Electric Locomotive Equipment, November 1933: DL&W Belt Railway of Chicago
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, October 1940: Atchinson, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Co.
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, February 1937: Bethlehem Steel Co.
    Maintenance Instructions
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, May 1936: Univ. Atlas Cement.
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, October 1937: Bethlehem Steel Co.
    300 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment: United Fruit
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, March 1937
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1940: Elgin, Joliet and Eastern Railway Co.
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, December 1937: The Reading Co
  - Operation and maintenance manuals, 16 vols. (Box 59)
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, March 1938: New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, October 1939: Rock Island Railroad
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, November 1939: Youngstown and Northern Railroad
    600 HP Oil -Electric Locomotive Equipment, May 1937: Reading Railroad
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1940: Green Bay and Western Railroad Co.
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1940: Boston and Maine Railroad
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, September 1939: Wabash Railroad, Southern Pacific Railroad, Maine Central Railroad, Minneapolis and St. Louis Railroad
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, February 1940: Kansas City Terminal Railway Company
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, February 1940: Minnesota Transfer Railway
    900 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, January 1939: Minnesota Transfer Railway
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1939: Erie
    600 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, February 1939: NY Central Railroad
    1000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1939: Atchinson, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Co.
    2000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, December 1939: The Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railway, Co.
    1000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, March 1940: Michigan Limestone and Chemical Company
    1000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, November 1939: Manufactures Railway
  - Operation and maintenance manuals, 15 vols. (Box 60)
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, December 1939: Southern Pacific Co., Boston and Maine Railroad, Northern Pacific Railway, Buffalo Creek Railroad Co., Wabash Railway Co. CMSTP&P, DL&W
    1000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, October 1939: C., M., St.P. & P.R.R., Manufacturers Railway Co.
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, September 1940: Southern Railway Co., T.P.-M.P.T.R.R. of N.D., Massena Terminal Railroad Co., Gulf Mobile and Ohio Railroad Inland Steel Co., American Steel and Wire Co., Green Bay and Western Railroad
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, May 1940: Des Moines Union Railway, Terminal Railroad Assn.-St. Louis, Missouri Pacific Railroad Co., Northern Pacific, New York Central Railroad, Reading Railroad Co., Elgin Joliet and Eastern
    1000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1940: Elgin Joliet and Eastern, South Buffalo Railway, Spokane, Portland and Seattle
    4000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, January 1941: Cincinnati, New Orleans and Texas Pacific Railways
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, December 1939: Southern Pacific Co., Boston and Maine Railroad
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, March 1940: The Elgin, Joliet, and Eastern Railway Co.
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment: New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Co.
    1000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1940: Oliver Mining Company
    660 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, April 1941
    Description Operation and Maintenance Instructions
    2000 HP Diesel-Electric Locomotive Equipment, July 1940: Mobile and Ohio Railroad Company
    Description, Operation and Maintenance Instructions (900 HP Single Cab Control)
  - Operation and maintenance manuals, 21 vols. (Box 61)
    Operating and Service Instructions: Forced Recirculation Steam Generators
    Symposium on Diesel Locomotive Engine Maintenance: May 11 and 12, 1953 at Schenectady, NY
    Symposium on Spectrographic Analysis of Diesel Engine Lubricating Oil: May 5 and 6, 1952 at Schenectady, NY
    Description, Operation and Maintenance Instructions 660 HP Single Cab Control 362 Motors
    Description, Operation and Maintenance Instructions 900 HP 486-A 2 Generator M.U. Control
    Specification #3476A (NY 46066)
    Electrical Equipment on 5-600 HP Oil Electric Locomotives
    Electrical Equipment on 5-900 HP Oil Electric Locomotives
    Specification No. 3477A (NY 460066)
    Description, Operation and Maintenance Instructions 600 HP 386-A Motors
    Instructions for Operating and Maintaining the Oil-Electric Locomotive Oil Engines
    Instruction Manual for the Operation of Railway Equipment
    Safety: Rules and Safe Practices
    Maintenance Manual: Model 567A Engines
    Handbook for Trouble Shooting and Operation on Diesel Locomotives
    Enginemen’s Operating Manual Model F7
    Operating Manual Model F3
    Operating Manual 600 and 1000 HP switching Locomotives
    Code of Rules Governing the Condition of, and Repairs to, Freight and Passenger Cars
    Interstate Commerce Commission Accounting Classifications for Steam Railroads
    Manual: Construction and Maintenance Section
  - Administrative
    - Alco Review Newsletter, 2 vols. (Box 62)
    - Administration Manuals, 1915-1935; 3 vols. (Box 62)
    - Management Guide, 3 vols. (Box 62)
    - Supervisory Development Program, 3 vols. (Box 62)
    - Supervisory Development Program, 3 vols. (Box 63)
    - Public Relations Handbooks, 8 vols. (Box 63)
    - Financial Practices Manuals, 2 vols. (Box 63)
    - Special Reports and Studies
      - Booster Cases, 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Heat Exchangers, 2 vols. (Box 63)
      - Korean National Railroad, 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Manufacture of Diesel-Electric Locomotives in India, 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Recovery Vehicle, 1 volume (Box 63)
    - Quality Control Manual, 1 volume (Box 63)
    - Rogers Locomotive Co. preliminary steam locomotive designs, 1905-1907 (Box 63)
    - Testing and Design, 7 vols. (Box 63)
    - Loose Materials from Notebooks
      - Alco-General Electric Advertising (Box 63)
      - Alco-General Electric News, 1950-1951 (Box 63)
      - Alco Products Review, 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Bulletins and Manuals, 3 vols. (Box 63)
      - Cylinder Head Machining, 2 vols. (Box 63)
      - Factory Rebuild Service, 1957 (Box 64)
      - Product Information (Box 64)
      - Property Inventory, 1939 (Box 64)
      - Reprints
        - Advertising (Box 64)
        - Articles (Box 64)
      - Standards: General Practice (Box 64)
      - Standards: Guide to Standards (Box 64)
      - Standards: Purchasing Practice (Box 64)
    - Armed Tank Manufacturing Proposal, 1 volume (Box 65)
    - Property Lists and Assessment, 1 volume (Box 65)
  - Photograph albums
    - Industry, 2 volume (Oversize 11)
    - Ships, 1 volume (Oversize 11)
  - Promotional Material
    - President's Export Award, 1 volume (Box 65)
    - Diesel-Electrics for Mexico, 3 vols. (Box 65)
    - Locomotives for Portugal, 3 vols. (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Les Locomotives a l'Exposition de 1900, 1 volume; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging, 6/03
- Miscellaneous
  - Brass Printer's Plate-Locomotive (Box 67)
  - Alco Equipment in the Field, index (Box 67, 68)
  - The ALCO Products Story, Print #1, circa 1952; alco_003; special effects of merging scenes are used; 35mm film
    Film licensed by the State of New York: No. Lic A-94904. This documentary film gives an overview of the implementation and manufacturing of new ALCO products. The film shows scenes of construction and factory workers at the job; engineers working in labs; demolition of buildings and construction of a skyscrapers; airplane; train; car assembly factory; aerial view of a factory site; foundry and coal mining lines; river bridges; business meetings; the establishment of the manufacturing process of the Nickel Plated Pipe and the heat exchangers products in 1951.
  - The ALCO Products Story, Print #2, circa 1952; alco_004; 35mm film
    Film licensed by the State of New York: No. Lic A-94905. This documentary film gives an overview of the implementation and manufacturing of new ALCO products. Most likely contains extra scenes.
  - The Other Company Part 1 and 2 [copy 1], 1954-1955; alco_001; sales presentation about products made by ALCO other than locomotives; meant to be used with filmstrips or 35 mm slides, has audible “next slide” tones; Vinyl record; running time 18:37
  - The Other Company Part 1 and 2 [copy 2], 1954-1955; alco_002; sales presentation about products made by ALCO other than locomotives; meant to be used with filmstrips or 35 mm slides, has audible “next slide” tones; Vinyl record; running time 18:37
  - Scrapbooks
    - News clippings (loose sheets), 1943 (Oversize 10)
    - "Publicity coverage / Dedication / Army Package Power Reactor / April 29, 1957", publicity regaridng opening of nuclear reactor (Oversize 12B)
- Display materials
  - Designs and aketches, also includes color prints of locomotives suitable for framing/exhibit (NYC, nickel-plated, etc.) (Oversize 2A)
  - Designs and aketches (Oversize 2B)
  - Photographs (Oversize 3A)
  - Photographs, color reproductions, includes color prints of locomotives suitable for framing/exhibit (NYC, nickel-plated, etc.) (Oversize 3B)
  - Designs and sketches, original artwork, ink drawings; annotations suggest they were for publication in non-technical brochure (Oversize 4)
  - Sketches, photographs, Schenectady Works plan, flip charts for PR/marketing, photos of U.S. Army missiles, launchers, transport cars (Oversize 5)
  - Photographs (Oversize 6)
  - Photographs, original and reproduction (printed), including a few of tanks (Oversize 7)
    Feb 2019: Package rehoused; some material placed into new Oversize 13.
  - Photographs (Oversize 8)
  - Photographs (Oversize 9)
  - Photographs (Oversize 10)
  - Miscellaneous, original and reproduction photographs, drawings, sketches, etc.; subjects include Schenectady, Auburn, Chile, more (Oversize 13)
- Ledgers
  - Shell Atlas, 1 volume
  - Railroad Data, 1946-1951; 3 vols.; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging, 6/16/03
  - Ames Pump Company, 1928-1937; journal entries; 1 volume
  - Atlantic Equipment Company, 1906; 1 volume
  - C.S-T. & W. Co., Ltd., General Journal (full name not given); 1 volume
  - Heat Transfer Products, Inc.
    - Ledger, 1929; 1 volume
    - Journal Entries, 1928-1931; 1 volume
  - Manchester Ledgers, 2 vols.
  - McIntosh & Seymour Corporation, 1931; 1939; 2 vols.
  - Manchester Locomotive Works, 1901; 1 volume
  - Richmond Locomotive & Machine Works, 1898
    - Ledger
    - Sales Book
    - Cash Book
    - Journal
  - Rogers Locomotive Works, 1902-1906; 4 vols.
  - Transamerican Construction Company, 1931; 1936; 2 vols.
  - Walco Manufacturing Company, 1915-1918; 1 volume
  - American Locomotive Company, 1937; cash book; 1 volume
  - American Locomotive Sales Corporation
    - Trial Balances, 1916-1938; 1 volume
    - Journal Entries, 1913-1919; 1920-1922; 2 volume
    - Ledgers, 1920; 1931,; 1936,; 1940
  - American Locomotive Automobile Company
    - Ledgers, 1905; 1907; 2 vols.
    - Journal, 1905; 1907; 2 vols.
  - Alco Products, Inc.
    - Journal Entries, 1931-1933; 1934-1937; 2 volume
    - Ledgers, 1929; 1931,; 1936,; 1957; 4 vols.
  - American Locomotive Company
    - Trial balances, 1916-1938; 1 volume
    - Trial balances, various companies
    - Trial balances, 1938
    - Trial balances, 1939
    - General Ledger Entries, 1930-1936; 1937; 2 vols.
    - Journals-Comptroller's Office, 1901-1907; 5 vols.
    - Ledgers-Comptroller's Office, 1901-1936; 16 vols.
    - Register of Contracts, 1901-1940; 21 vols.
    - Financial Statistics, 1909-1918; 6 vols.
    - Letter and Document Books
      - Affiliated Companies, 1930-1935; 1 volume
      - American Locomotive Company, Ames Pump Company, 1943-1944; 1 volume
      - Board of Directors, 1919-1937; 1922-1937; 2 volume
      - By-Laws, Railway Steel-Spring Merger, Annual Reports, 1906-1937; 1 volume
      - Directors, Alco, Montreal, Sales Corporation, 1917-1935; 1 volume
      - Dividends, Alco, Montreal, Sales Corporation, 1905-1932; 1 volume
      - Donations, 1907-1934; 1 volume
      - Funds and Purchasing, 1909-1937; 1 volume
      - Loans and Securities, 1906-1937; 1 volume
      - Property Expenditures, 1901-1922; 1 volume
  - Railway Steel-Spring Company
    - Denver, 1903; 1910; 3 vols.
    - General Journal, 1902-1926; 18 vols.
    - General Ledger, 1902-1934; 7 vols.
    - Recapitulation Sales and Credits, 1919; 1922; 2 vols.
    - Journal Entries and Trial Balances, 1929-1934; 9 vols.
    - Cost of Sales, 1932-1934; 1 volume
  - Montreal Locomotive Works
    - General Ledger Entries-Comptrollers Office, 1908-1929; 9 vols.
    - Unfinished Work Journal Entries, 1914-1919; 1 volume
    - Journal Entries, 1906-1930; 39 vols.
  - American Locomotive Company
    - Journal Entries
      - [General], 1910-1939; 98 vols.
      - Beaumont, 1954-1959; 9 vols.
      - Latrobe, Chicago Heights, 1954-1959; 11 vols.
      - Ordnance, 1951-1955; 13 vols.
      - Summary, 1953; 1 volume
      - Schenectady, Dunkirk, Auburn, Cincinnati, 1955-1957; 3 vols.
      - General Office, 1954-1957; 3 vols.
      - Export Company, 1954-1957; 1 volume
      - General Office and Plant, 1954-1960; 66 vols.